<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Kerim Friedman</title>
    <description>Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/kerim&quot;&gt;@kerim on Micro.blog&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    <link>https://micro.oxus.net/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 19:02:16 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 19:02:16 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>What is a microblog, and why do you need one?</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was trying to set up a microblog and didn’t even know it. I was personally motivated by a sense that giving all my content to Facebook and Twitter is giving up too much. Although I blog regularly on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anthrodendum.org&quot;&gt;anthro{dendum}&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to start using &lt;a href=&quot;https://keywords.oxus.net&quot;&gt;my personal blog (Keywords)&lt;/a&gt; more for sharing all that stuff that I normally post to social media. I didn’t want to stop using social media, I just wanted to have more of a sense of ownership over the content I post there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that it is so much easier to post stuff to Facebook and Twitter from my phone using their apps, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://pragmaticcode.com/linky/&quot;&gt;Linky&lt;/a&gt;,  than it is to post to my own blog. Part of that is my fault. I moved my blog off of WordPress to a very geeky platform called &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. While it is possible to post to Jekyll from my phone using &lt;a href=&quot;https://workingcopyapp.com&quot;&gt;Working Copy&lt;/a&gt; and some scripts you can find on the web, the whole process isn’t that great. It was while I was Googling for something better that I discovered the wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog&quot;&gt;Micro.Blog&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://manton.org&quot;&gt;Manton Reece&lt;/a&gt;. Within five minutes I gave up trying to automate posting to Keywords from my phone and instead paid for a microblog . . . which is what you are looking at now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-microblog&quot;&gt;What is Micro.Blog?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the most basic level, Micro.Blog is just a hosted Jekyll blog. Why would you pay $5 a month for this when you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/using-jekyll-as-a-static-site-generator-with-github-pages/&quot;&gt;host your own Jekyll blog for free on Github&lt;/a&gt;? That’s because of the app, which makes it super easy to write posts, including posts with images, directly from your phone or desktop. Moreover, you can host it &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.micro.blog/2015/custom-domains/&quot;&gt;under your own domain name&lt;/a&gt; (as I do). Even better, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.micro.blog/2016/mirroring-to-github/&quot;&gt;mirror your entire blog&lt;/a&gt; to your own Github account in realtime, so you are never locked in. You can go back to hosting it yourself whenever you like!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;but-thats-not-all---&quot;&gt;But that’s not all . . .&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what kind of pixie dust Manton uses, but he did much more than just make a nice interface for hosting your own Jekyll blog. He set out to make an open alternative to Twitter that functions like an old-time blog. Within the app or on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog&quot;&gt;Micro.Blog&lt;/a&gt; website you have a Twitter-like timeline with &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/replies&quot;&gt;@replies&lt;/a&gt;. You can also follow other users and “like” their posts. And you don’t even need to host your microblog with Manton to benefit from this - you can push posts from your own microblog as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;but-wait-theres-more---&quot;&gt;But wait, there’s more . . .&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said at the top, my goal was never to leave social media behind, just to get a sense of ownership of my content. Micro.Blog understands that and in the same way that social media is parasitic on the traditional web, Micro.Blog is parasitic on social media. You can easily set up for all your posts to be forwarded to your Twitter and Facebook accounts — something that &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; still makes hard to do. (See here for the rules regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.micro.blog/2018/timeline-rules/&quot;&gt;what part of your post gets posted&lt;/a&gt; to social media, depending on the length of the post and whether or not it contains an image.) And, of course, because it is just a blog, you have a nice old-fashioned RSS feed as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Micro.blog isn’t for everyone. It is still a work in process and there are a few kinks to work out. Although there are a lot of tricky things about Facebook and Twitter, this adds another layer of complexity. (Not everyone wants to learn how to format posts in &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.micro.blog/2017/markdown/&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;.) But it already works better for me than what I was doing before, so I’m personally really impressed with it. Even if the alternative social-feed aspects never evolve into a Facebook destroyer, you still have a very nice way to update a Jekyll blog from your phone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the social media aspect though, I do think that sites like Micro.Blog and Mastodon will eventually need to think about implementing their own algorithmic timelines. Even though part of the motivation for moving away from Facebook and Twitter is that we have increasingly less control over what they show us, I don’ t think there are many people who want to see &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of my posts, not to mention all of your other friends who share too much on social media. If they work well, algorithms should show us more of what we want to see and less of what we don’t. I think a really successful open alternative to Facebook or Twitter will eventually need to think about what an open algorithm might look like. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 17:55:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/06/what-is-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/06/what-is-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/3357470&quot;&gt;Hualien quakes sign that Taiwan has entered 100-year earthquake cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On Feb. 4, there were 28 earthquakes… 12 occurring in a single hour, the largest of which was a magnitude 5.8… with ten more earthquakes on Monday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 13:14:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/06/hualien-quakes-sign.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/06/hualien-quakes-sign.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://afropunk.com/2018/02/conan-obrian-wasnt-ready-haitian-little-girls-anti-colonialism/&quot;&gt;Conan O’Brien wasn’t ready for this Haitian little girl’s anti-colonialism&lt;/a&gt; (click through to watch the video)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 10:01:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/06/conan-obrien-wasnt.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/06/conan-obrien-wasnt.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone wrote up the conference I attended last year at the University of Nottingham in Ningbo: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.languageonthemove.com/debating-language-standardization/&quot;&gt;Language Standardization and Linguistic Variation in Asia from Sociolinguistic Perspectives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 09:53:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/06/someone-wrote-up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/06/someone-wrote-up.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2018/02/trump-modi-india-south-asia-accent-apu/551696/&quot;&gt;Making Fun of How South Asians Talk: A History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 09:24:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/06/making-fun-of.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/06/making-fun-of.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump…&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsweek.com/trump-fire-and-fury-smart-genius-obama-774169&quot;&gt;communicates at the lowest grade level of the last 15 presidents&lt;/a&gt;, according to a new analysis of the speech patterns of presidents going back to Herbert Hoover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.oxus.net/uploads/2018/91496c9d00.jpg&quot; width=&quot;410&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 07:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/06/president-donald-trumpcommunicates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/06/president-donald-trumpcommunicates.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Very happy to have my microblog now running under my own domain: &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.oxus.net&quot;&gt;micro.oxus.net&lt;/a&gt; You can even subscribe to it with an RSS reader! And my entire microblog is being mirrored to my github repository if I ever want to self-host it. Support the open web!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 21:03:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/05/very-happy-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/05/very-happy-to.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Regarding &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2014/10/20/pets-allowed&quot;&gt;this New Yorker article&lt;/a&gt; about emotional-support animals: yes, abuse of the system hurts people with real needs, but perhaps this “abuse” is allowed to happen because we just like having animals around?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 18:25:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/05/regarding-this-new.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/05/regarding-this-new.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The problem with micro.blog and mastodon is that they are trying to do away with algorithmic timelines altogether; but the thing is that people actually &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; algorithmic timelines! What we need is a network with open source, transparent, user-configurable, algorithms!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 12:25:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/05/the-problem-with.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/05/the-problem-with.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This story, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/dc-politics/high-skilled-indian-workers-rally-for-trumps-merit-based-immigration-plan/2018/02/03/702e617e-08fd-11e8-8777-2a059f168dd2_story.html&quot;&gt;High-skilled Indian workers rally for Trump’s merit-based immigration plan&lt;/a&gt;,” reminded me of the film &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gentleman&#39;s_Agreement&quot;&gt;Gentleman’s Agreement&lt;/a&gt; where Gregory Peck’s Jewish secretary is worried that ending workplace descrimination at his newspaper will lead to “the ‘wrong Jews’ [being] hired and will ruin things for the few Jews working there now.” &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 10:47:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/05/this-story-highskilled.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/05/this-story-highskilled.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Why I am testing out micro.blog</title>
        
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Those were great years — but then a few tragedies happened: Google Reader came out, and then, almost worse, it went away. Worse still was the rise of Twitter and Facebook, when we decided it would be okay to give up ownership and let just a couple companies own our communication… Even if those companies had the public interest in mind — and they most definitely do not — they hold far too much power over something too fundamental to give up: our own human voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/2018/02/01/why_micro_blog_is_not_another_app_net&quot;&gt;Why Micro.blog is Not Another App.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 10:18:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.oxus.net/2018/02/05/why-i-am.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kerim.micro.blog/2018/02/05/why-i-am.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
